Guide to the Ann Brewer Knox papers, 1935-2011 MS2305
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ann Brewer Knox papers
circa 1935 - 2011
1977-2011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Knox, Ann B
Velletri, Ann
MS2305
36 Linear Feet 71 document boxes, 1 flat box
Ann Brewer Knox was a Washington D.C. area writer and teacher of poetry and short fiction. Her writings were widely published in journals and books. This collection contains drafts of poetry and short stories, book manuscripts, publications, personal journals, correspondence, publication, teaching and other professional materials, clippings, and floppy disks documenting her personal and professional writing career. The bulk of the material dates from 1977 to 2011.
Arrangement note
Organized into two series: Poetry and short fiction and Personal and professional papers.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Related Materials
The Innisfree Poetry Journal posted online her previously unpublished chapbook of poems titled Eve Learns the Word Want http://authormark.com/artman2/publish/Innisfree15ANN_KNOX4.shtml
In additon, the Knox family donated correspondence from three generations of Knox women to the Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America, The Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, Harvard University.
Biographical note
Ann Brewer Knox (1926-2011) was a Washington D.C. area writer and teacher of poetry and short fiction. Her writings were widely published in journals and books.
Ann Brewer was born in Buffalo, N.Y. on 1926 January 31, and her father, George Brewer, was a playwright who co-authored "Dark Victory." She graduated from Vassar College in 1946 and later earned a master's degree in education from Catholic University in 1970. In 1981, she received a master's degree in fine arts from Warren Wilson College (Goddard College). Ann Brewer married M. Gordon Knox in 1947, who worked for the Foreign Service. Including six children, the Knox family lived in Washington, D.C., Moscow, London, and Karachi, Pakistan during Gordon Knox's Foreign Service deployments. Ann and Gordon divorced in 1989.
As she began to write and teach full-time, Knox built a small cabin in the southern Pennsylvania Appalachian foothills. Much of her poetry reflected the natural world of her retreat and her experiences as a daughter, wife, mother, and "recovering hostess." Knox was the author of several full length poetry collections: Stonecrop (1988), Staying in Nowhere (1996), and Breathing-In (2011). She authored a book of short stories entitled Late Summer Break (1995). Her poetry was also published in two chapbooks, "Reading the Tao at Eight" (2008) and "The Dark Edge," (2004) and in numerous literary journals and reviews, including Alaska Quarterly Review, Atlanta Review, Baltimore Review, Blueline, Comstock Review, Cumberland Poetry Review, Green Mountains Review, MacGuffin, Nimrod, Plum Review, Poerty, Poets On, Potomac Review, and WordWrights. Staying is Nowhere was a winner of the SCOP-Writer's Center Co-Publication Prize in 1996, and Stonecrop was a winner of the Washington Writers' Publishing House Prize. Knox was one of the editors of the Antietam Review and a poetry editor for the Washington Writers Publishing House. She taught poetry at workshops and at the Georgetown Day School.
Knox died of a stroke on 2011 May 10 shortly after a benefit poetry reading at Cacapon State Park in Berkeley Springs, W.V.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains drafts of poetry and short fiction stories, book manuscripts, publications, personal journals, correspondence, publication material, public relations material, writing workshops material, teaching material, clippings, and floppy disks documenting the personal and professional writing career of Ann B. Knox. The bulk of the material dates from 1977 to 2011, when Knox was active in this work. Some earlier material dates from her childhood, college years, and graduate studies, circa 1935 to 1977.
The material exhibits the stages of Knox's writing, from early drafts to published products, and her connections to other DC area poets and poetry groups. Her journals, which she regularly wrote from 1977 to 2011, contain information about her writing and daily life.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of of Ann Velletri, 2012 March 29 and 2012 June 11 (2012.038 and 2012.061).
Poetry -- 21st century; Poetry -- 20th century; Poetry; Writings; Creative writing; Velletri, Ann
- Poetry and short fiction, 1977-2011; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains drafts of poetry and short fiction stories, book manuscripts, publications, floppy disks, and CDs documenting the writing career of Ann B. Knox. The material dates from 1977 to 2011.
  Arrangement
  Organized into four subseries: Drafts; Book manuscripts; Publications; and Disks and CDs.
  - Drafts, 1977-2011; Series 1 Subseries 1
    This subseries contains drafts of poetry and short fiction stories. Some of the drafts include edits and revisions by Ann Knox and by the other people who read drafts of her writings. Occasionally pieces of correspondence and other material were filed by Knox with the drafts.
    Arranged alphabetically by folder/poem title.
    - Aderondacks village mountain, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aderondack village - tahawus, circa 1977; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - After a friend's wedding, circa 1985; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - After days of rain, 1989; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - After I wrote no, circa 1979; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - After sister's 65th reunion, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aha!, 2005-2006; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Air view, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Alaska, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alaska Journey, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alaska poems, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alaska poems, 1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Alexa, circa 1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Alexa, circa 2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Alexa, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Alexa, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alexa, nelly, sam, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Amazing events, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - And now us poems, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Andrew reflection, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Andrew the draw, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Anna, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Another kind of garden, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Approaching the Crone, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Arribada, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - At night I plunge, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Auction, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Aunt from the country, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Aunt without issue, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bat swarm, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Beach dream, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bear in autumn, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Beautiful boy, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Begin, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Being human, wanting something, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Being seen, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Belly dance, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Betrayal, circa 1985; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Better the sea, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Beyond gravity, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Beyond gravity, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Biker's girl, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Biography of a house, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bird of eye, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bird maddened by sound, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bird singing in the moonlight, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Blind in the forest, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Blood brother, 2002-2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Blood brother, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Blood brother, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Blood brother daniel, 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Blood brother (Joris A-F), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Blue skink, 2003-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Body language, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bones, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Bonsai, 1993; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Bonsai, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bonzai, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bonsai - collected family, 2003-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Bonsai - sarah, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bonzai, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Boucranion, circa 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Boyds-clarksburg exit, 1985-1986; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Boyds-clarksburg, 1987; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Boyds-clarksburg, 2001-2001; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Boyds-clarksburg, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bozeman montana, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Breathing, 2009-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Brief biography of amy thomas, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Brother, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Buck, 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Builder builds, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Buy yourself hounds, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Buzzards, 2001-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Buzzards - old, 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Calendar, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Caught moment, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Center of the world, 2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Ceremonial bronze, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ceremony, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Change, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Checking on iris, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Checking on iris, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Circle, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Clean copies of pub. poems, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Clearing a view, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Clematis, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Climbing echo mt., 2007-2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Close-out, 2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Coin, circa 1979-1980; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Compass reading, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Contempt, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Content, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Corrected story, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Crone, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Crone claims title, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Crone poems with hadad comments, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Crone remembers her husband, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Crone thanks her sister, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Crone's husband comes back, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Crossing south mt., undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Crow on the skylight, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Crow watcher, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Current in progress poems, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Current work desk 5/11, 2007-2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Cut, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Cut loose, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Danger, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Daniel, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Dark edge draft, circa 1999; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Dark side of praise, 2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Daughter's daughter, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Days glide by sonnet, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Dear dr. shipley, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Dear dr. shipley, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Deep freeze, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Desert, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Discoveries, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Dock, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Domain, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Domain - the draw (story), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Doors, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Drafts, circa 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Drafts Po's, circa 2006; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dream house, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Dreams of my daughter, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Drink for dorsey, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Drink for dorsey early draft, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Driving to the city, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Early po's didn't make it, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Early spring, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Easy, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Easy to love fragments, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Ebb, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Eclipse, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Eclipse paris 1912, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Edges, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Edges, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Edges, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Elizabeth, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Elizabeth, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Elizabeth, circa 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Elizabeth / sarah, circa 2000; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Ellie, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Emptiness, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Enter sorrow, 1999-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Envy, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Etcetera period, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Eve, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Eve drafts, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Eve drafts, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Eve drafts poems, 2005-2011; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Eve early drafts, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Eve early revisions, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Eve early revisions, circa 2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Except touch, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Except touch, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Exotics, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Expectation, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Expedition, circa 1994; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Exquisite corpse, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Fable, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Failed orchard, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - False rise (trout), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Family reunion, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Family reunion, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - February rain, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Few current concerns, 2007-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Fiction to circulate, 1994-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Finders, losers (shell hunter), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Firmness, commodity, delight, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Fish in water, 2008-2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Fisherman, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Flag, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Flag another mountain, 1992-1993; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Flag novel, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Flash, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Flight north / bearings, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Flowering, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Floyd, circa 1980-1985; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Flocal point, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - For a grandchild, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - For ma, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - For the first time, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Fossil, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Foul, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Fragments, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fragments fiction, 2001-2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Freight, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Friend leaves, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Fugue, circa 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Geode, 1979-1984; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Georgie, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Getting by, 2009; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Gift I would give you, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Gift of snowshoes, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Go somewhere you've not been before, 2007-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Going back, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Going into the canyon, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Gone for a fortnight, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Good bye, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Grams and checking on flag, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Grandfather / robinson crusoe, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Gray day, 2009-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Green, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ground cover, 2009-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Grow-up, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Gypsies, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hand hold, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Hanging basket (more than enough), 2009-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Hard ground, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hard ground, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Headed west, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Heironymus bosch is not a pornographer, 2007-2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Her grandson brings the crone a stone bird, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Her mother's house, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Hide the ring, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Hindu kush, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Hissam and Mary, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Hold still, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Hold still, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Hopper, circa 2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Hopper, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Hopper early ray carver comments, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - House in dorset, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - House (sonnet), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - How things work, 2007-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Hunting for amber on cabarete beach, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Hunting morels, 2008; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - I am a crow, 2005; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - I divorce you says the crone, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - I don't know, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - I dream old dylan came back, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - I have been searching, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - I learned of glaciers, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - I lived in a house, 2007; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - I lose a word, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - I need a few blind days / cabin / autumn fog / time out, circa 1977-1978; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - I tell you my dream at breakfast, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Ice house, 2007-2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - In memoriam, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - In progress, circa 1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - In the deli and other poems, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Innisfree, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Interview with a sculptor, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Island christmas, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - It (short poem), undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - It's so easy, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - It was in your eyes, circa 1977; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Ivan ivanich, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Jade stone, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Janek, 2002-2003; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Janek, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Janek, circa 2002-2004; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Janek, circa 2002; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Janek, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Joan Daw, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      General
      File also contains photographs
    - Jose, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Jumper, circa 1998; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Jumper, 1994-1997; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Jumper, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Just look at my kids, undated; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Killing time, 2010; Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 9, Folder 17)